Now that you have trained your first model,
最初のモデルの トレーニングが終了したこの時点で
there is something very important I want to discuss.
議論すべき 重要な事項があります
You might have seen in the assignment that we had a training set,
課題で見たかもしれませんが トレーニングセットの他に
as well as a validation set, and a test set.
評価セットと テストセットもありました
What is that all about?
これらはいったい何でしょうか?
Don't skip that part.
必ず確認してください
It has to do with measuring how well you're doing
処理の適切さの 測定に関係し
without accidentally shooting yourself in the foot, and
失敗を防ぐのに 役立ちます
it is a lot more subtle then you might initially think.
第一印象より はるかに微妙です
It's also very important because as we will discover later,
また 後で説明しますが 問題に対するパフォーマンスを測定する方法がわかれば
once you know how to measure your performance on a problem,
すでに半分は 解決したことになるため
you've already solved half of it.
その点からも非常に重要です
Let me explain why measuring performance is subtle.
パフォーマンスの測定が微妙なことである 理由を説明します
Let's go back to our classification task.
分類タスクに 戻りましょう
You've got a whole lot of images with labels.
ラベルについて 多くのイメージが手に入りました
You could say, okay, I'm going to run my classifier on those images, and
そこで これらのイメージに対して クラシファイ（識別器）を実行し
see how many I got right.
どの程度正しく得られたかを確認したいと考えるでしょう
That's my error measure.
これは誤差測定です
And then you go out and use your classifier on new images,
次に これまで見たことのない新しいイメージに対して
images that you've never seen in the past, and
クラシファイを使ってみます どれくらい正しい結果が得られるかを
you measure how many you get right, and your performance gets worse.
測定すると パフォーマンスは低下し
The classifier doesn't do as well.
クラシファイはうまく動作しません
So what happened?
何が起きているのでしょうか?
Well, imagine I construct a classifier that simply compares the new
作成したクラシファイは 新しいイメージをトレーニングセットにすでにある
image to any of the other images that I've already seen in my training set,
他のイメージと単純に比較し ラベルを返すだけであると
and just returns the label.
考えてください
By the measure we defined earlier, it's a great classifier.
前に定義した測定では 優れたクラシファイです
It would get 100% accuracy on the training set.
トレーニングセットでは 100%の精度を得られます
But as soon as it sees a new image, it's lost.
しかし 新しいイメージの場合は どうすればよいか
It has no idea what to do.
わからなくなります
It's not a great classifier.
優れたクラシファイではありません
The problem is that your classifier has memorized the training set, and
問題は このクラシファイは トレーニングセットを記憶しているだけで
it fails to generalize to new examples.
新しい例に一般化できていないことです
It's not just a theoretical problem.
単なる理論上の問題ではありません
Every classifier that you will build will tend to try and
作成されるすべてのクラシファイは トレーニングセットを記憶しようとする傾向が
memorize the training set.
あります
And it will usually do that very, very well.
通常 それは非常にうまく行われます
Your job though, is to help it generalize to new data instead.
しかし ここで必要なのは 新しいデータの一般化を助けることです
So, how do we measure generalization instead of measuring
それではクラシファイによるデータの記憶力を 測定するのではなく
how well the classifier memorized the data?
一般化の能力を測定するには どうすればよいのでしょう?
The simplest way is to take a small subset of the training set,
最も簡単な方法は トレーニングセットの一部を
not use it in training, and measure the error on that test data.
トレーニングに使用せずに そのテストデータの誤差を測定することです
Problem solved, now your classifier cannot cheat
問題は解決しました このクラシファイはテストデータを見ないため
because it never sees the test data, so it can't memorize it.
それを記憶できず カンニングできないのです
But there is still a problem,
しかしクラシファイのトレーニングは通常は
because training a classifier is usually a process of trial and error.
試行錯誤のプロセスなので まだ問題があります
You try a classifier, you measure its performance and
あなたはクラシファイを試し パフォーマンスを測定してから
then you try another one and you measure again.
別のクラシファイを試して 再び測定します
And another, and another, you tweak the model, you explore the parameters,
さらに別のクラシファイを試して測定し モデルを微調整し
you measure, and finally, you have what you think is the perfect classifier.
パラメーターを調べ 測定し 最終的に完璧なクラシファイと考えられるものができあがります
And then after all this care you've taken to separate your test data from
トレーニングデータから テストデータを分離して
your training data and only measuring your performance on the test data,
テストデータだけで パフォーマンスを測定した後
now you deploy your system in a real production environment.
システムを実際の 運用環境に展開します
And you get more data and you score your performance on that new data and
さらにデータを取得し 新しいデータでパフォーマンスを評価すると
it doesn't do nearly as well.
それほどよくありません
What can possibly have happened?
何が起きているのでしょうか?
What happened is that your classifier has seen your test data, indirectly,
実は このクラシファイは あなた自身の目を通して
through your own eyes.
間接的にテストデータを見ていたのです
Every time you made a decision about which classifier to use, which parameter
使用するクラシファイや 調整するパラメーターを決定するたびに
to tune, you actually give information to your classifier about the test set.
実際はテストセットについての情報を クラシファイに与えていたのです
Just a tiny bit, but it adds up.
1つ1つは小さなことでも それが蓄積されます。
So over time, as you run many, and
時間が経ち実行する実験が増えるほど
many experiments, your test data bleeds into your training data.
テストデータは トレーニングデータに流出していきます
So what can you do?
どうすればよいのでしょう?
There are many ways to deal with this.
これに対処するには多くの方法があります
I'll give you the simplest one.
ここでは最も簡単な方法を示します
Take another chunk of you training set and hide it under a rock.
トレーニングセットから別の塊を取り出し それを岩の下に隠します
Never look at it until you have made your final decision.
最終的な決定を下すまで それを見てはいけません
You can use your validation set to measure your actual error, and
評価セットを使って 実際の誤差を測定でき
maybe the validation set will bleed into the training sets.
おそらく評価セットは トレーニングセットに流れ出します
But that's okay because you'll always have this test set
しかし 問題ありません 現実のパフォーマンスを
that you can rely on to actually measure your real performance.
実際に測定するために利用できるこのテストセットが 常にあるからです